{
  "sourceFile": "2021-International-Geography-Bee-Regional-Finals-Set-2-Round-1.txt",
  "count": 10,
  "items": [
    {
      "qno": 1,
      "question": "This island's largest and oldest lake is Lake Biwa, which is named for its resemblance to a certain instrument. Awaji Island is linked to this other island by a bridge to the city of Kobe. This island's lowest point is Hachigorata and its highest point is Mt. Fuji. This island is also home to the cities of Kyoto and Osaka. For the point, name this largest island of Japan, which contains Tokyo.",
      "answer": "Honshu"
    },
    {
      "qno": 2,
      "question": "Bouvet Island, located in the Subantarctic, is a dependency of this country. Much of this country's power comes from a dam on the River Glomma [[GLO-mah]], whose mouth flows through the city of Fredrikstad. Though governed by this country, the Svalbard archipelago is an unincorporated and visa-free jurisdiction. For the point, name this kingdom whose border with Sweden runs along the Scandinavian Mountains.",
      "answer": "Kingdom of Norway"
    },
    {
      "qno": 3,
      "question": "One of these structures named for the Guarani people is located in southern Brazil and is composed of Piramboia Formation sandstones. The Great Artesian Basin in Australia is widely considered the largest one of these structures in the world. One of these structures in the Great Plains is called Ogallala. For the point, name these layers of permeable subsurface rock which act as reservoirs for fresh water.",
      "answer": "Aquifers"
    },
    {
      "qno": 4,
      "question": "One ethno-religion practiced by these people features a six-day pilgrimage to the city of Lalish. The city of Erbil serves as the capital to a territory named for these people. These Yazidi-practicing people have been the subject of a genocidal campaign by ISIL. For the point, name this ethnic minority who are seeking to form an independent state in northern Iraq and Syria.",
      "answer": "Kurds"
    },
    {
      "qno": 5,
      "question": "This city is served by the world's largest desalination plant at the port of Jebel Ali. This city's The Palm hotel notably has underwater rooms. This city is home to archipelagos of artificial islands shaped like a map of the world. This city is home to the tallest skyscraper in the world, which is known as the Burj [this city]. For the point, name this most populous city in the United Arab Emirates.",
      "answer": "Dubai 2020-21 Geography Bee Two - 2021-03-22 Geography Bee Two - Round 1"
    },
    {
      "qno": 6,
      "question": "In this country in 1974, Jane Goodall discovered an ongoing \"war\" between chimpanzee tribes in the Gombe Stream National Park. This country's Ngorongoro [[en-gor- on-GOR-oh]] Conservation Area is home to the Olduvai Gorge, a ravine spanning 50 kilometers of the Great Rift Valley. This country is home to the highest mountain in Africa, Mount Kilimanjaro. For the point, name this East African country whose largest city is Dar es Salaam.",
      "answer": "United Republic of Tanzania"
    },
    {
      "qno": 7,
      "question": "Cities on this body of water include Sundsvall and Vaasa, on this body of water's northern arm, the Gulf of Bothnia. 114 miles of Russian coastline touch this body of water by way of the Kaliningrad Oblast. This body of water's name is also used to refer collectively to the former Soviet states of Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania. For the point, name this northern European body of water spanning from Denmark to Finland.",
      "answer": "Baltic Sea"
    },
    {
      "qno": 8,
      "question": "One type of these structures named for Grove Karl Gilbert consists of coarse sediments and most commonly forms near freshwater lakes. When these structures are composed of high amounts of gravel, they can form namesake \"braids.\" When these structures cause stream splitting, they are referred to as a \"bird's foot.\" For the point, name these triangular regions formed from deposited sediment where a river discharges into a lake or ocean.",
      "answer": "River Delta"
    },
    {
      "qno": 9,
      "question": "This island contains Mt. Tuba, which is in the Barisan Mountains, and this island's highest point is Mt. Kerinci [[keh-RIN-chee]]. The northern end of this island is home to the province of Aceh [[AH-cheh]]. This island is separated from the Malay Peninsula by the Straits of Malacca and is separated from Java in the south by the Sunda Strait. For the point, name this westernmost of the major Indonesian islands.",
      "answer": "Sumatra"
    },
    {
      "qno": 10,
      "question": "The coast of this state was first mapped in 1592 by Juan de Fuca, including the strait that now bears his name. This state hosts part of the Cascade Volcanic Arc, including Mount Jefferson, Mount Hood, and the Three Sisters. Seventy percent of this state's population lives in the Willamette Valley, which stretches from Newberg to Eugene. For the point, name this West Coast state whose largest city is Portland.",
      "answer": "Oregon 2020-21 Geography Bee Two - 2021-03-22 Geography Bee Two - Round 1"
    }
  ]
}